<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>感悟</title>
    <link href="/Wuxiaowu.github.io/2025/02/20/thingk1/"/>
    <url>/Wuxiaowu.github.io/2025/02/20/thingk1/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>我时常会自己冒出一下<strong>奇奇怪怪的想法</strong>，感悟这个分类就记录一下我自己的想法吧，这里的文章我不想组织文本逻辑，也不想按照结构化逻辑组织，既然是奇奇怪怪的想法，我就不局限于文章的体裁，段落的结构，一些词语是否合适，目的就是写个痛快。现在有了自己的博客网站，我更加可以畅所欲言，也不必担心审核是否通过。</p><p><strong>博客</strong>的目的从本身角度出发来时记录一下自己的想法，同时做为一个程序员也需要有一个平台记录自己的学习内容。写博客也是一个好习惯，让我们有一些输出，当把自己的一些想法写下来之后，一方面能梳理一下自己的逻辑能力，另一方面是自己成长的记录。多年之后会看自己曾经写下来的一些文字内容，多少也是一种情怀。人生其实就是闲下来看看未来，回忆一下过去，忙的时候认真专注于当下。再加几个精彩的瞬间。回看一生，其实每个人都是历史长河中的一粒尘埃，所以我觉得我觉得我有权利把我的生命价值发挥到最大化。这样才不枉我在历史长河走一遭，将来即使没有为他人创造出价值，最起码在我自己的青春岁月中有我奋斗的痕迹。我是一个具有浪漫主义色彩的人，但是在具有浪漫主义色彩的同事，我又是被世俗的枷锁裹挟。我爱人曾经和我说，你要努力去追求你自己的未来，她不会给我设置任何障碍。但是从我个人角度来说，我可以张开翅膀去飞翔，可以世俗的一些枷锁带给我的一些束缚，其实还是让我需要考虑很多。但是倒是不至于限制我。只不过需要我的做事情的事情考虑很多，可能也是责任的驱使吧。</p><p>曾经的我是个<strong>急功近利的小伙子</strong>，现在的我。。。。好像还有有急功近利，不过相比以前好多的了，具体表现在哪些方面呢，first(首先)，曾经的我学习技能的时候，不太注重技能的基本功，比方说打篮球，或者是刚到大学的时候学习计算机的知识。我曾经打球的时候，经常看到别人花哨的运球，过人，和稳定的投篮。但是自己却一直没有相应的技能，就开始模仿，比如说花哨的运球过人，其实所有的运球过人都是日积月累的基本功打扎实了，在实战中才能运用出来。同时比方说对于计算机知识，当时学院里面的光荣榜上面有保研的学长，进入互联网的大厂的学长，本科毕业年新30W+的学长，我也就开始学了一些技术框架，翻着招聘网站，学了以及上层应用的开发框架，刷算法题。不过后来随着学习的深入。越来越发现，了解计算机底层的运行原理，才能真正的去开发好程序，上层的应用开发其实复杂点在于业务逻辑。而业务逻辑对于我来说是个比较虚的东西。走到现在慢慢理解那句“慢就是块”的含金量的，很多事情有时候人不经历其实也不会明白的。其实用工匠精神把不断打磨一件产品，知道现在目前很多大厂出的产品每一个环节都是经过3-5轮的不断打磨才能在市场上获得一定的地位。其实推过来讲，一个人也是，只有不断经历打磨，不断经历挫折。。。。，你就会经历不完的挫折。</p><p>两年前读过<strong>王阳明传记</strong>，也研究了一些阳明心学相关的内容，过了两年之后，不断经历，才隐隐约约明白了书中讲的一些内容，大概理解了”心之理“，所有的东西都是从自己的心出发的，写到这里突然想起来大二的时候心理学老师和我说过一句话是“你怎么看别人，那你一定是那样的人” 其实总体的意思类似，就是吾心即世界。有时候感叹很多中西方的理念虽然说形式上不同，但其实其背后的本质是一样的，可能这就是所谓的道吧。王树国校长说过一句话“伟人都是研究规律，然后按照规律办事的”， 其实我也认为世界的运行是有规律的，大到太阳东升西落下，小到 ”心之理“。所以阅读人类历史上一些伟大的经典著作还是有很大作用的。和伟人对话，吸取他们总结的规律教训。也不一定就要用这些东西去做成功什么事情，简单的去探究这个世界的奥秘就已经让我感到很幸福了。</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>感悟</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>感悟</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Best English Learning Tools for IELTS Succes</title>
    <link href="/Wuxiaowu.github.io/2025/02/20/Success/"/>
    <url>/Wuxiaowu.github.io/2025/02/20/Success/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>In this blog, I will showcase a selection of tools that I have found invalubale throught my IELTS preparation. These resources are designed to save your both time and money, while effectively enhancing your English proficiency.</strong></p><span id="more"></span><h1 id="Writting"><a href="#Writting" class="headerlink" title="Writting"></a><strong>Writting</strong></h1><h2 id="essay"><a href="#essay" class="headerlink" title="essay"></a><strong>essay</strong></h2><p><strong>link:</strong>   <a href="https://www.essay.art/ielts">https://www.essay.art/ielts</a></p><p>This website offer two daily opportunities for you to submit your writing and receive a detaild assessment. It provides accurate scoring based on IELTS criteria, along with constructive feedback on your response, task achievement, vocabulary and grammar.</p><p>One of its standout features is its scoring accuary, making it a great tool for IELTS writing parcitice.However, the sample essays provided tend to use hight-level vocabulary, which may not be the best reference for beginner. Still, if you’re looking for a relibale way to simulate the IELTS wirting test and get insightful feedback, this platform is definitely worth trying .</p><h1 id="Speaking"><a href="#Speaking" class="headerlink" title="Speaking"></a><strong>Speaking</strong></h1><p>Practicing <strong>English speaking</strong> is essential for improving fluency, pronunciation, and confidence. One of the best ways to do this is by using <strong>AI-powered voice tools</strong>. Among them, <strong>ChatGPT stands out as an excellent choice</strong> because it allows you to practice <strong>any topic</strong> with <strong>your preferred voice</strong>. Most importantly, it’s <strong>free</strong>, which means you can <strong>save money</strong> while honing your ability to <strong>organize answers effectively</strong>.</p><p>If you’re struggling with <strong>English pronunciation</strong>, the best approach is <strong>consistent practice</strong>—<strong>repeating words and sentences over and over again</strong>. Additionally, <strong>imitating native speakers</strong> is crucial. Many learners struggle because they don’t know how certain sounds are initially produced. Learning a language is largely about <strong>mimicking native speech patterns</strong>, and AI tools can help <strong>accelerate your progress efficiently</strong>.</p><p>Here are some powerful <strong>AI-driven tools</strong> that can help you practice speaking English effectively:</p><p><strong>chatGPT,</strong><br><strong>DeepSeek,</strong><br><strong>Gemini</strong></p><h2 id="Combine-Writing-and-Speaking-Practice-with-AI-Tools"><a href="#Combine-Writing-and-Speaking-Practice-with-AI-Tools" class="headerlink" title="Combine Writing and Speaking Practice with AI Tools"></a><strong>Combine Writing and Speaking Practice with AI Tools</strong></h2><p>Did you know that <strong>writing and speaking skills</strong> can be practiced together? By integrating <strong>AI-powered tools</strong>, you can enhance both aspects of your English learning journey efficiently.</p><h3 id="Step-1-Get-Feedback-on-Your-Writing"><a href="#Step-1-Get-Feedback-on-Your-Writing" class="headerlink" title="Step 1: Get Feedback on Your Writing"></a><strong>Step 1: Get Feedback on Your Writing</strong></h3><p>After finishing an <strong>IELTS essay</strong>, submit it to an <strong>AI-powered writing assessment website</strong>. These platforms not only provide <strong>detailed feedback</strong> but also offer <strong>model essays</strong>, allowing you to learn <strong>advanced vocabulary and grammar structures</strong>.</p><h3 id="Step-2-Convert-Text-to-Speech"><a href="#Step-2-Convert-Text-to-Speech" class="headerlink" title="Step 2: Convert Text to Speech"></a><strong>Step 2: Convert Text to Speech</strong></h3><p>Once you’ve reviewed your essay, use <strong>LuvVoice</strong> (or a similar AI tool) to <strong>convert your text into natural-sounding speech</strong>. Download the generated voice file and use it for pronunciation practice.</p><h3 id="Step-3-Practice-Speaking-with-AI-Assistance"><a href="#Step-3-Practice-Speaking-with-AI-Assistance" class="headerlink" title="Step 3: Practice Speaking with AI Assistance"></a><strong>Step 3: Practice Speaking with AI Assistance</strong></h3><p>Read your essay <strong>out loud</strong>, following the AI-generated voice. This method helps you <strong>correct pronunciation</strong>, <strong>improve fluency</strong>, and <strong>internalize advanced expressions</strong> effortlessly. Through repeated practice, you not only enhance your <strong>speaking skills</strong> but also reinforce your <strong>writing abilities</strong> by remembering useful sentence structures.</p><p>By leveraging AI tools effectively, you can <strong>boost both writing and speaking skills simultaneously</strong>, making your IELTS preparation more efficient and engaging.</p><p><strong>link of luvvoice:</strong><br><a href="https://luvvoice.com/zh#google_vignette">https://luvvoice.com/zh#google_vignette</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>IELTS</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>tools</tag>
      
      <tag>AI</tag>
      
      <tag>IELTS</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
